Contact

smdshoaib2000@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/smdshoaib (LinkedIn)

www.stopstalk.com/user/profile/ smdshoaib (Other)

Athenasquare.org/smdshoaib (Portfolio)

linktr.ee/smdshoaib (Personal)

Top Skills

AWS

AWS CloudFormation Spring Security

Languages

Hindi (Full Professional)

Telugu (Limited Working)

English (Professional Working)

Urdu (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

SQL (Intermediate)

Java Coding Challenge Bootcamp

Infosys Certified Java SE8

Professional

NPTEL - Programming in Java

Learning Python

Honors-Awards

Certificate of Merit

Best Project of Client for FY2022 Q2

C Programming - Gold Badge (5*)

Java - Gold Badge (5*)

Silver Award

Mohammed Shoaib S.

SDE-1 at Delta Air Lines | Java Full Stack Dev

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Summary

Java Developer with almost 5 years of experience in the aviation and shipping domain.

In my role as a Software Developer within Delta Airlines' eTicketing and Financial Document Management department, I was responsible for the modernization of various applications, including the development of new systems and their deployment on the AWS cloud platform.

My areas of interests include R&D, implementing automation, and code optimisation using Java8, Java21 features.

I have been honoured with Delta's Platinum Award (1x), Gold Award (2x), Silver Award (3x).

Companies Offered during 1st Switch:
Barclays, Delta Air Lines, Thought works, Dish Network Technology,
Wissen Technology, Tejas Network, Virtusa, Aidetic, TCS

Companies Offered during Fresher:

Infosys, Accenture, Wipro, Mindtree, Cognizant, HCL, Capgemini, Altran, Legato (Carelon), StackNexus, Artech

Experience

Delta Air Lines

3 years 2 months

SDE-1

October 2023 - Present (1 year 9 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

•# Designed, Built applications from scratch following API first approach, infra setup, deployed in AWS

- •# Worked on various POCs which helped in reducing manual intervention and integrated the same in real time apps.
- # Refactored, optimised many applications to improve performance.
- *# Working on project NDC (New Distribution Capability) an initiative by IATA (International Air Transport Association)
- •# Integrated OIDC authentication for web-app to promote role based access.
- •# Implemented Java Virtual Threads to improve parallel processing of kafka messages.

Associate SDE

May 2022 - September 2023 (1 year 5 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- # Part of eTicketing, Financial Document Management (FDM) team.
- •# Enhanced and Modernised existing applications and build new applications which are used by Delta and AIR4 (AIR4 is Delta Air Lines hosted operational application systems and software support provided to partner airlines as software as a service)
- •# Improved application performance by Query Optimisations.
- •# Worked on modernising one of the critical module of ETicketing.

StackRoute

Trainee

June 2022 - July 2022 (2 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

*#Completed Training on Java Spring Full Stack with cloud native skills on OpenShift cloud platform program as part of Emerging Talent Program by Delta Tech Hub

Infosys

1 year 4 months

Digital Specialist Engineer

May 2021 - April 2022 (1 year)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- # Unit : STG (Strategic Technology Group)
- # Worked as API Developer for client CMA CGM (Shipping Company)
- *# Certified in Open Source Professional, Full Stack Professional and API Professional.
- # DQ 70, Top 1% Digital Quotient (DQ)
- #Cleared OA for the role of Specialist Programmer

Systems Engineer Specialist

January 2021 - April 2021 (4 months)

- •# Trained on Java Angular Full Stack Java11, Springboot, Hibernate, Rest API, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap4, Angular.
- # Training Score: 91%
- # Reskill Training on Docker, Kubernetes.

All MNCS

1 year

Accenture - Trainee Pre Joining January 2021 - January 2021 (1 month)

Cognizant - Trainee Pre Joining September 2020 - December 2020 (4 months)

- •#Completed Cognizant Early Engagement Training Program and cleared all Assessments.
- •#Completed Assimilation Program and cleared the Assimilation test to join as Full Stack Engineer for the Cognizant Digital Engineering Unit

Mindtree - Trainee Pre Joining June 2020 - December 2020 (7 months)

- *#Completed Pre Joining Learning Program on Java, Completed all weekly Assignments.
- •#Successfully cleared Assessments and interview process to get Date Of Joining.

Wipro - Trainee Pre Joining February 2020 - June 2020 (5 months)

*#Completed Wipro PJP - Pre Joining Program on Java Full Stack and cleared all Assessments.

Education

Chaitanya Bharathi Institute Of Technology Proddatur Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science and Engineering · (2016 - 2020)

Sri Gayatri Junior College, Kadapa intermediate, MPC · (2014 - 2016)

Nirmala English Medium High School, Kadapa